<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="ayahuasca_content"><font size="14"><b>Ayahuasca (Banisteriopsis caapi)</b>
    is a psychotropic tea obtained from Amazonian plants. Ayahuasca induces visions, intense emotion and recollection of personal memories.
        \n\nPsychoactive substances affect the brain and cause people to experience changes in their mood, thinking, and behavior.
        \n\nAyahuasca enhances self-acceptance and beneficial mindfulness capacities.
        \n\nAvailable evidence suggests its potential to treat various psychiatric disorders.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Ayahuasca</b></font>

        \nAccording to current research, Ayahuasca may protect brain cells and stimulate neural cell growth.
        \n\nIt may also boost mood, improve mindfulness, and treat depression and addiction disorders, though more research is needed to confirm these effects.

        \n\nAyahuasca is used for suicide prevention, depression, grief, and many other conditions, but there is no good scientific evidence to support these uses.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nAvoid the consumption of alcohol, stimulants, opiates and other drugs in the weeks before ayahuasca.
        \n\nIt is also very important to reduce expectations about the ses- sion (unrealistic expectations are frequent) while establishing a definite intention (what you would like to get out of the session).

        \n\nThough Ayahuasca was traditionally used for religious and spiritual purposes by specific populations, it has become popular worldwide among those who seek a way to open their minds, heal from past traumas, or simply experience an Ayahuasca journey.

        \n\nIt\’s strongly recommended that Ayahuasca only be taken when supervised by an experienced shaman, as those who take it need to be looked after carefully, as an Ayahuasca trip leads to an altered state of consciousness that lasts for many hours.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nAyahuasca contains chemicals that can cause hallucinations, tremors, dilated pupils, increased blood pressure, nausea, and vomiting.
        \n\nLife-threatening side effects and death have also been linked with ayahuasca use.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="betel_nut_content"><font size="14"><b>Betel nut (Areca catechu)</b>
    is the seed of the fruit of the areca palm.
        \n\nThe areca nut is the seed of the areca palm, which grows in much of the tropical Pacific, Southeast and South Asia, and parts of east Africa.
        \n\nThe common names, preparations and specific ingredients vary by cultural group and individuals who use it.
        \n\nBetel nut is a stimulant drug, which means it speeds up the messages travelling between the brain and the body.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Betel nut</b></font>

        \nIt was said to expel wind, kill worms, remove phlegm, subdue bad odors, beautify the mouth, induce purification, and kindle passion.
        \n\nBecause of its CNS stimulating effects, betel nut is used in a manner similar to the western use of tobacco or caffeine.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThe seed is separated from the outer layer of the fruit and may be used fresh, dried, boiled, baked, roasted or cured.
    \n\nBetel nut is chewed alone or in the form of quids, a mixture of tobacco, powdered or sliced betel nut, and other ingredients.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nIt can cause stimulant effects similar to caffeine and tobacco use.
        \n\nIt can also cause more severe effects including vomiting, diarrhea, gum problems, increased saliva, kidney disease, chest pain, abnormal heart beat, low blood pressure, shortness of breath and rapid breathing, heart attack, coma, and death.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="cannabis_content"><font size="14"><b>Cannabis (Cannabis sativa)</b>
    , also known as marijuana among other names, is a psychoactive drug from the Cannabis plant.
        \n\nNative to Central and South Asia, the cannabis plant has been used as a drug for both recreational and entheogenic purposes and in various traditional medicines for centuries.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Cannabis</b></font>

        \n1. Lowering blood pressure
        \n2. Reducing inflammation
        \n3. Preventing relapse in drug and alcohol addiction
        \n4. Treating anxiety disorders
        \n5. Treating gastrointestinal (GI) disorders
        \n6. Preventing seizures
        \n7. Fighting cancer

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nCannabis can be consumed in several ways; inhaled, ingested, or applied topically, and there are significant differences in the way the effects are felt.
        \n\nDried cannabis can be rolled into a cigarette, called a \“joint\” or in a cigar, called a \“blunt\”. It can be smoked in a water pipe or \“bong\” or vaped in an e-cigarette or other vaping devices.
        \n\nCannabis edibles can be brewed as tea, infused into drinks, or mixed into food and ingested as candies, cookies, and brownies. Consuming cannabis edibles like brownies or cookies is considered by some youth to be a less risky way of consuming than smoking it.
        \n\nAll cannabis products are legal for retail sale only at licensed outlets. Cannabis should be produced by licensed producers and purchased only from licensed vendors. Evidence suggests that illegal cannabis products can be contaminated with pesticides and harmful chemicals.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nRegular use might increase the risk of lung cancer. Some people develop a type of lung disease called emphysema.
        \n\nSchizophrenia: Using cannabis might make symptoms of schizophrenia worse. Quitting smoking: Using cannabis might make it harder to quit smoking.
    \n\nWhen taken by mouth: Cannabis is possibly unsafe when used in large amounts or long-term. Edible cannabis containing 50 mg or more of THC has been linked with serious side effects.
        \n\nRegularly taking large amounts of cannabis might cause cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome (CHS). CHS leads to severe nausea and vomiting that doesn\'t respond to typical anti-nausea drugs. Also, using cannabis for at least 1-2 weeks can cause dependence.

        \n\nWhen inhaled: Cannabis is possibly unsafe when used in large amounts or long-term. Smoking or vaping cannabis can cause breathing problems. Vaping products containing THC have been linked to serious lung injury. Regularly smoking cannabis may cause CHS and/or dependence.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="coca_content"><font size="14"><b>Coca (Erythroxylum coca)</b>
    is any of the four cultivated plants in the family Erythroxylaceae, native to western South America.
        \n\nCoca is known worldwide for its psychoactive alkaloid, cocaine.

        \n\nThe leaves of the coca plant are the source of cocaine, which is an illegal drug that is used nasally, injected, or smoked for mind-altering effects. Cocaine is also an FDA-approved Schedule II drug.
        \n\nThis means cocaine can be prescribed by a healthcare provider, but the process is strictly regulated.
        \n\nThe worry about cocaine is that it is unsafe and highly addictive.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Cocaine</b></font>

        \nPeople chew coca leaves to relieve hunger and fatigue and to enhance physical performance.
        \n\nCoca extracts are used for stimulating stomach function, causing sedation, and treating asthma, colds, and other ailments.
        \n\nCoca tea is used for altitude sickness in the Peruvian Andes and elsewhere.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nA form of cocaine that can be applied to the skin is available by prescription. It is used to numb eye, nose, and throat pain; and to narrow blood vessels.

        \n\nThe coca leaf has been chewed and brewed for tea traditionally for centuries among its indigenous peoples in the Andean region – and does not cause any harm and is beneficial to human health.

        \n\nWhen chewed, coca acts as a mild stimulant and suppresses hunger, thirst, pain, and fatigue. It helps overcome altitude sickness.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nThe cocaine contained in coca leaves is LIKELY UNSAFE when taken by mouth for medicinal uses and UNSAFE when taken by mouth for recreational uses.
        \n\nCocaine is illegal and can cause hyperactivity, restlessness, excitement, migraine headaches, seizures, strokes, heart attacks, aneurysms, high blood pressure, and liver and kidney failure.
        \n\nAs little as 1/4 of a teaspoon of cocaine can be deadly.
        \n\nCocaine is highly addictive.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="jimsonweed_content"><font size="14"><b>Jimsonweed (Datura stramonium)</b>
    , known by the common names thorn apple, jimsonweed, devil\'s snare, devil\'s trumpet, or angel\'s trumpet, is a species of flowering plant in the nightshade family Solanaceae.
        \n\nIts likely origin was in Central America, and it has been introduced in many world regions.
        \n\nThe leaves and seeds are used to make medicine.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Jimsonweed</b></font>

        \nThe leaves and seeds are used to make medicine. Despite serious safety concerns, jimson weed is used to treat asthma, cough, flu (influenza), swine flu, and nerve diseases.
        \n\nSome people use it as a recreational drug to cause hallucinations and a heightened sense of well-being (euphoria).

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThe leaves can be dried and rolled to make cigarettes. The leaves and seeds are sometimes dried, pulverized, and ignited in order to breathe the fumes for the treatment of asthma.
        \n\nThe leaves and seeds are decocted in water to make a tea, but this practice is very dangerous
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nSide effects from ingesting jimson weed include tachycardia, dry mouth, dilated pupils, blurred vision, hallucinations, confusion, combative behavior, and difficulty urinating.
        \n\nSevere toxicity has been associated with coma and seizures, although death is rare.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="oppium_poppy_content"><font size="14"><b>Oppium poppy (Papaver somniferum)</b>
    , commonly known as the opium poppy or breadseed poppy, is a species of flowering plant in the family Papaveraceae.
        \n\nIt is the species of plant from which both opium and poppy seeds are derived and is also a valuable ornamental plant, grown in gardens.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Oppium poppy</b></font>

        \nThe poppy plant contains morphine, codeine, thebaine, and other opium alkaloids known for their pain-relieving, calming, and sleep-inducing properties.
        \n\nThese compounds are often found in pharmaceutical drugs intended for these uses.
        \n\n1. Rich in nutrients and antioxidants
        \n2. May contain pain-relieving compounds
        \n3. May boost heart and skin health
        \n4. May aid digestion
        \n5. May safeguard against certain illnesses
        \n6. May enhance fertility

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThe opium poppy has a number of uses of great economic importance:
        \n\n1. Its seeds are edible, and are used, especially in Central Europe but also throughout the rest of the world
        \n\n2. The seeds provide a good-quality oil which is used for human consumption, especially in northern Europe
        \n\n3. In view of its high content of quick-drying substances, the first juice extracted is used to make oil varnishes, soap, greases, perfume, etc.
        \n\n4. The seeds are also used in pharmacy for making emulsions
        \n5. Oil-cake made from poppy-seeds is excellent. cattle feed and a first-class fertilize

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nRegular use of opium may cause:
        \n1. tolerance - needing to use more to get the same effect.n
        \n2. irregular periods and difficulty having children.
        \n3. loss of sex drive.
        \n4. constipation.
        \n5. dependence on opium.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="peyote_content"><font size="14"><b>Peyote (Lophophora williamsii)</b>
    is a small, spineless cactus which contains psychoactive alkaloids, particularly mescaline.
        \n\nPeyote is a Spanish word derived from the Nahuatl peyōtl, meaning \"caterpillar cocoon\", from a root peyōni, \"to glisten\". Peyote is native to Mexico and southwestern Texas.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Oppium poppy</b></font>

        \nVarious Indigenous cultures that revere the plant believe that it has a vast number of health benefits for the body.
        \n\nFor example, they may use peyote to treat a number of ailments, from snake bites and wounds to systemic problems such as diabetes, skin conditions, and general pain.

        \n\nDespite serious safety concerns, peyote is used for treating fevers, joint pain (rheumatism), and paralysis.
        \n\nPeople apply peyote to the skin for treating fractures, wounds, and snakebite. Peyote is also used as a recreational drug because it can cause hallucinations.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nPeyote buttons (the \“crown\” or top of the peyote cactus) look like disc-shaped buttons.
        \n\nThey can be fresh or dried. People can chew them or soak them in water to make an intoxicating liquid.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nWhen taken by mouth: Peyote is UNSAFE for use. It can cause nausea and vomiting, anxiety, paranoia, fear, and emotional instability.
        \n\nIt can also raise blood pressure, heart rate, and respiration rate. Changes in vision, drooling, headache, dizziness, and drowsiness may also occur.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="salvia_content"><font size="14"><b>Sage of the diviners (Salvia divinorum)</b>
    is a plant species with transient psychoactive properties when its leaves are consumed by chewing, smoking, or as a tea. The leaves contain opioid-like compounds that induce hallucinations.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Sage</b></font>

        \nVarious Indigenous cultures that revere the plant believe that it has a vast number of health benefits for the body.
        \n\nFor example, they may use peyote to treat a number of ailments, from snake bites and wounds to systemic problems such as diabetes, skin conditions, and general pain.

        \n\nDespite serious safety concerns, peyote is used for treating fevers, joint pain (rheumatism), and paralysis.
        \n\nPeople apply peyote to the skin for treating fractures, wounds, and snakebite. Peyote is also used as a recreational drug because it can cause hallucinations.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nSalvia is a drug that produces visual hallucinogenic effects similar to those people can experience with narcotics such as LSD.
        \n\nSome users claim that they have mystical and spiritual experiences after taking it.

        \n\nSalvia plants are traditionally noted for their antioxidant effects and ability to enhance \'head and brain\' function, improve memory, quicken the senses, and delay age-associated cognitive decline.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nWhen taken by mouth: Salvia divinorum is POSSIBLY UNSAFE.
        \n\nIt can cause serious side effects including dizziness, slurred speech, confusion, paranoia, hallucinations, and delusions.

        \n\nWhen inhaled: Salvia divinorum is POSSIBLY UNSAFE. It can cause serious side effects including dizziness, slurred speech, confusion, paranoia, hallucinations, and delusions.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="tobaco_content"><font size="14"><b>Tobacco (Nicotiana tabacum)</b>
    is the common name of several plants in the genus Nicotiana of the family Solanaceae, and the general term for any product prepared from the cured leaves of these plants.
        \n\nMore than 70 species of tobacco are known, but the chief commercial crop is N. tabacum.

        \n\nTobacco is made from the leaves of tobacco plants. It contains nicotine, which is an addictive drug.
        \n\nWhen you smoke tobacco in cigarettes, cigars or pipes, you absorb toxic and cancer-causing chemicals that affect your health.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Tobacco</b></font>

        \nTobacco isn\'t famous for its health benefits. But now scientists have succeeded in using genetically modified tobacco plants to produce medicines for several autoimmune and inflammatory diseases, including diabetes.

        \n\nTobacco has always been considered as a medicinal plant. Before its use as a smoking material, it has been used as a traditional medicine for common illnesses.
        \n\nIt is claimed to be an antiseptic, sedative, emetic, purgative and useful in relieving pain.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThe predominant use of tobacco is by smoke inhalation of cigarettes, pipes, and cigars.
        \n\nSmokeless tobacco refers to a variety of tobacco products that are either sniffed, sucked, or chewed.

        \n\nTobacco leaves are usually harvested, then dried, and used in pipe smoking, or in cigarettes. However, they are also increasingly used in cuisine where they impart a subtle, bitter heat.
        \n\nThey may be cooked with rice, or used to smoke meats like wild game and fish.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nSome of the conditions and diseases that can be caused by smoking:

        \n\nCancer
        \nBreathing problems and chronic respiratory conditions
        \nHeart disease, stroke and blood circulation problems
        \nDiabetes
        \nInfections
        \nDental problems
        \nHearing loss
        \nVision loss
        \nFertility problems
        \nOsteoporosis and menopause\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

</resources>