<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="bael_content"><font size="14"><b>Bael (Aegle marmelos)</b>
        , commonly known as bael, also Bengal quince, golden apple, Japanese bitter orange, stone apple or wood apple, is a rare species of tree native to the Indian subcontinent and Southeast Asia.
        \n\nIt is present in India, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, and Nepal as a naturalized species.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Bael</b></font>

        \nBael contains chemicals called tannins, flavonoids, and coumarins. These chemicals help to reduce swelling (inflammation).
        \n\nThis might help treat asthma, diarrhea, and other conditions. Also, some of these chemicals help to reduce blood sugar.
        \n\nBael is loaded with a myriad of nutrients which include vitamins A, B1, B2, C and minerals calcium, potassium and iron.
        \n\nThe host of plant compounds in bael is beneficial in treating tuberculosis, hepatitis, ulcer and digestive problems.
        \n\nFurthermore, it is also a good source of tannins which aid in treating cholera.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \n1. Bael Juice (Sharbat)
        \na. Take ½- 1 cup of Bael Sharbat.
        \nb. Mix with water and drink it after taking light food once or twice a day.
        \nc. Drink this to get rid of diarrhea or dysentery.

        \n\n2. Bael Churna
        \na. Take ¼-½ teaspoon Bael churna.
        \nb. Mix with water and take after lunch and dinner.

        \n\n3. Bael Tea
        \na. Take 1-2 teaspoon of roasted Bael pulp.
        \nb. Add hot water to it.
        \nc. Stir for 1-2 minutes.

        \n\n3. Bael Squash
        \na. Take 3-4 teaspoons of Bael pulp in a glass.
        \nb. Pour some cold water to it.
        \nc. Stir for 2-3 minutes.
        \nd. Strain and add water.
        \ne. Drink this for cooling effects on the stomach.



        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nLarge amounts may cause stomach upset and constipation.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="catnip_content"><font size="14"><b>Catnip (Nepeta cataria)</b>
        , commonly known as catnip, catswort, catwort, and catmint, is a species of the genus Nepeta in the family Lamiaceae, native to southern and eastern Europe, the Middle East, Central Asia, and parts of China.
        \n\nIt is widely naturalized in northern Europe, New Zealand, and North America.

        \n\nIt\'s a plant that is easy to grow in North America and has feather-like, light-green foliage with lavender flowers.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Catnip</b></font>

        \nHistorically, catnip was used for diarrhea, gas, and stomach cramps. It\'s said to relieve muscle spasms in the intestinal tract.
        \n\nDrinking catnip tea may soothe the digestive system.
        \n\nMany groups of people have traditionally used catnip tea to relieve infants\' colic and help babies to sleep at night.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThese days, humans who consume catnip generally drink it as a tea. The tea is widely believed to soothe anxiety and insomnia, as well as digestive troubles.
        \n\nYou can purchase catnip tea bags, or you can make it yourself.
        \nIf catnip has a positive effect on your cat, you can use it as a training aid or an occasional treat.
        \n\nSome suggested uses for catnip are the following:

        \n\n1. Rub catnip into your cat’s scratching post to encourage use
        \n2. Place catnip in toys to promote active play and exercise
        \n3. Sprinkle catnip in a new environment to encourage shy cats to be comfortable and help cat-to-cat introductions go smoothly
        \n4. Use catnip in the carrier or crate to reduce anxiety and create a sedative state during car trips



        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nCupful amounts of catnip tea have been consumed without serious side effects. However, catnip is POSSIBLY UNSAFE when smoked or taken by mouth in high doses (many cups of catnip tea, for example).
        \n\nIt can cause headaches, vomiting, and a feeling of being ill.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="cinnamon_content"><font size="14"><b>Cinnamon (Cinnamomum verum)</b>
    , called true cinnamon tree or Ceylon cinnamon tree, is a small evergreen tree belonging to the family Lauraceae, native to Sri Lanka.
        \n\nThe inner bark of several other Cinnamomum species is also used to make cinnamon, but C. verum has a subtler flavor that makes it preferred for certain recipes


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Cinnamon</b></font>

        \n<b>1</b>. Cinnamon can reduce inflammation, which has the added benefit of relieving soreness and pain.
        \n\n<b>2</b>. Cinnamon has more antioxidant activity than both oregano and garlic. Antioxidants help protect your body by lowering the impact of oxidative damage from free radicals in your cells.
        \n\n<b>3</b>. Cinnamon has been shown to improve insulin sensitivity in muscle and fat tissues, increase the uptake of glucose, and improve glycogen synthesis in the liver, making it easier for the body to regulate blood sugar in people with type-2 diabetes.
        \n\n<b>4</b>. There are some studies that indicate cinnamon might help prevent Alzheimer’s disease.
        \n\n<b>5</b>. Some compounds of cinnamon might slow down the growth of cancerous cells.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nThere are four easy ways to ingest cinnamon.
        \n\n1. Sprinkle it on food. The simplest way to consume cinnamon is to sprinkle a little of it on your food, such as on toast.
        \n\n2. Make a tea. The chemicals in cinnamon are water soluble and make a great tea.
        \n\n3. Take capsules. You can take cinnamon supplement capsules, but check the dosage amount on the package.
        \n\n4. Swallow it with honey. Honey with cinnamon is a common remedy for sore throats and coughs. It can help alleviate pain and soreness caused by bronchitis.



    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nAs with all supplements, it’s important to control the dose and not take too much. The coumarin in Cassia cinnamon may cause side effects.

        \n\nToo much coumarin may cause liver damage, especially in individuals with pre-existing liver disease.
        \n\nOne of the benefits of cinnamon is that it can help to regulate blood sugar. One of the side effects of too much cinnamon, however, is that it can drop your blood sugar too low.
        \n\nSome people are born with or develop an allergy to cinnamon. Some symptoms of a cinnamon allergy include skin irritation and an upset stomach every time you ingest it.\n\n
</font>
</string>

    <string name="henna_content"><font size="14"><b>Henna (Lawsonia inermis)</b>
    , also called Egyptian privet, tropical shrub or small tree of the loosestrife family (Lythraceae), native to northern Africa, Asia, and Australia.
        \n\nThe leaves are the source of a reddish-brown dye, known as henna, which is commonly used for temporary body art and to dye fabrics.
        \n\nThe plant bears small opposite leaves and small, fragrant, white to red flowers. In addition to being grown for its dye, it is used as an ornamental.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Henna</b></font>

        \nHenna contains substances that might help fight certain infections.
        \n\nThere is also some information that henna might decrease the growth of tumors, prevent or reduce spasms, decrease inflammation, and relieve pain.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nHenna is sometimes applied directly to the affected area for dandruff, eczema, scabies, fungal infections, and wounds.
        \n\nIn manufacturing, henna is used in cosmetics, hair dyes, and hair care products; and as a dye for nails, hands, and clothing. People also use henna on the skin as temporary \“tattoos.\”

        \n\nHistorically, henna has been used for severe diarrhea caused by a parasite (amoebic dysentery), cancer, enlarged spleen, headache, jaundice, and skin conditions. These days, people take henna for stomach and intestinal ulcers.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nHenna seems to be safe for most adults when used on the skin or hair. It can cause some side effects such as inflammation of the skin (dermatitis) including redness, itching, burning, swelling, scaling, broken skin, blisters, and scarring of the skin. Rarely, allergic reactions can occur such as hives, runny nose, wheezing, and asthma.

        \n\nHenna is considered to be UNSAFE when taken by mouth. Accidentally swallowing henna requires prompt medical attention. It can cause stomach upset and other side effects.\n\n
    </font>
</string>

    <string name="lavender_content"><font size="14"><b>Lavender (Lavandula angustifolia)</b>
    is an evergreen plant native to the Mediterranean. Its flower and oil have a popular scent and are also used as medicine.
        \n\nLavender contains an oil that seems to have calming effects and might relax certain muscles. It also seems to have antibacterial and antifungal effects.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Lavender</b></font>

        \n1. May Help Improve Sleep
        \n2. Could Help Treat Skin Blemishes
        \n3. May Offer a Natural Remedy for Pain
        \n4. Reduce Blood Pressure and Heart Rate
        \n5. Could Relieve Asthma Symptoms
        \n6. Lessens Menopausal Hot Flashes
        \n7. Help Combat Fungus Growth
        \n8. Potentially Promotes Hair Growth

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nDosing. Lavender is used in many different types of products. A specific lavender oil product (Silexan) has most often been used by adults in doses of 80-160 mg by mouth daily for up to 10 weeks.
        \n\nLavender essential oil is commonly used in aromatherapy and various topical products such as massage oils and lotions.

        \n\nDisplay the dried bunch in an antique vase or quart jar. After you have tired of your dried flowers, you can strip the lavender off the stem, store in a muslin bag for fragrance.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nSide effects might include constipation, diarrhea, and headache. When applied to the skin: Lavender is possibly safe. It\'s usually well-tolerated, but can sometimes cause skin irritation.\n\n
    </font>
</string>

    <string name="marigold_content"><font size="14"><b>Marigold (Tagetes)</b>
    thrive in full sunshine and can often withstand very hot summers. African and signet marigolds are drought tolerant, while French marigolds are more tolerant of wet conditions.
        \n\nIf planted in shade and cool, moist areas, marigolds are prone to powdery mildew and won’t bloom well.

        \n\nMarigolds are a favorite, no-fuss annual that can bring the color of sunshine to your garden, as well as butterflies, bees, ladybugs, and other beneficial insects.
        \n\nGive them full sun and some well-draining soil and watch them bloom from late spring until fall.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Marigold</b></font>

        \nThe main medicinal applications of marigold are skin conditions of all kinds, including contusions, bruises and varicose veins.
        \n\nMinor skin injuries and inflammation can also be successfully treated. Marigold ointment promotes wound healing for eczema and sunburns.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nUsing Marigolds in Cooking- Rich in flavonoids, antioxidants, and vitamin C-Marigolds can used in many dishes from tossing them fresh into your salad to baking them into cakes.
        \n\nThey make a pretty topping for cakes and cupcakes, and can be candied in sugar.


        \n\nThe tender green leaves are edible.They can be eaten raw, in salads, or boiled. Given their powerful flavor, they can also spice up and flavor any vegetable soup.
        \n\nWe can also eat them in tortillas and egg rolls, mixed with petals, which gives us a very tasty and cheerful result.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nAn allergic reaction to this product is unlikely, but seek immediate medical attention if it occurs. Symptoms of an allergic reaction include: rash, itching, swelling, dizziness, trouble breathing.
        \n\nIf you notice other effects not listed above, contact your doctor or pharmacist.\n\n
    </font>
</string>

    <string name="neem_content"><font size="14"><b>Neem (Azadirachta indica)</b>
    is a natural herb that comes from the neem tree, other names for which include Azadirachta indica and Indian lilac. The extract comes from the seeds of the tree and has many different traditional uses.
        \n\nNeem is known for its pesticidal and insecticidal properties, but people also use it in hair and dental products.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Neem</b></font>

        \nNeem contains chemicals that might help reduce blood sugar levels, heal ulcers in the digestive tract, prevent pregnancy, kill bacteria, and prevent plaque from forming in the mouth.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nNeem oil can be applied to the skin or mixed with shampoo or creams.
        \n\nIt\'s considered safe for oral intake when diluted with alcohol or taken in tablet or powder form.
        \n\nHowever, regulation of neem is limited, so many products aren\'t tested for safety or purity.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nTaking neem seeds and seed oil by mouth is likely unsafe in children. Serious side effects in infants and small children can happen within hours after taking neem oil.
        \n\nThese serious side effects include vomiting, diarrhea, drowsiness, seizures, loss of consciousness, coma, and death.\n\n

    </font>
</string>

    <string name="peppermint_content"><font size="14"><b>Peppermint (Mentha × piperita)</b>
    is a hybrid mint, a cross between watermint and spearmint.
        \n\nIndigenous to Europe and the Middle East, the plant is now widely spread and cultivated in many regions of the world.
        \n\nIt is occasionally found in the wild with its parent species.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Neem</b></font>

        \nPeppermint may help improve digestion, freshen your breath and improve concentration.
        \n\nAdditionally, this mint has antibacterial properties and may improve allergy symptoms, headaches and clogged airways.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nPeppermint is used to add flavor or fragrance to foods, cosmetics, soaps, toothpaste, mouthwashes, and other products, and it may have some medicinal uses.
        \n\nA person can also use dried or fresh peppermint (Mentha piperita) leaves to brew tea.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nPeppermint can cause some side effects including heartburn, dry mouth, nausea, and vomiting. When applied to the skin: Peppermint oil is likely safe.\n\n
    </font>
</string>




    <string name="rosemary_content"><font size="14"><b>Rosemary (Salvia rosmarinus)</b>
    is a hybrid mint, a cross between watermint and spearmint. Indigenous to Europe and the Middle East, the plant is now widely spread and cultivated in many regions of the world.
        \n\nIt is occasionally found in the wild with its parent species.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Rosemary</b></font>

        \nis an herb native to the Mediterranean region. The leaf and its oil are commonly used in food and also to make medicine.
        \n\nRosemary seems to increase blood circulation when applied to the scalp, which might help hair follicles grow.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nRosemary is a rich source of antioxidants and anti-inflammatory compounds, which are thought to help boost the immune system and improve blood circulation.
        \n\nLaboratory studies have shown rosemary to be rich in antioxidants, which play an important role in neutralizing harmful particles called free radicals.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nTaking large amounts of rosemary can cause vomiting, sun sensitivity, and skin redness.
        \n\nWhen applied to the skin: Rosemary oil is possibly safe for most people.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>
</resources>