<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="blackberry_content"><font size="14"><b>blackberry (Rubus)</b>
     is a large and diverse genus of flowering plants in the rose family, Rosaceae, subfamily Rosoideae, with over 1,350 species.
        \n\nRaspberries, blackberries, and dewberries are common, widely distributed members of the genus.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Blackberry</b></font>

         \n1. They\'re packed with vitamin C. Just one cup of raw blackberries has 30.2 milligrams of vitamin C
        \n2. They\'re high in fiber. Most people don\'t get enough fiber in their diet
        \n3. Great source of vitamin K
        \n4. High in manganese
        \n5. May boost brain health
        \n6. Helps support oral health

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nA popular method is to consume blackberries with breakfast. People can include them as part of a fruit salad with plain or Greek yogurt.
        \n\nAlternatively, they can add blackberries to cereals, including porridge.
        \n\nAnother simple way to include blackberries into a diet is in fruit smoothies.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nTannins can cause nausea and even vomiting in people with sensitive stomachs. People with chronic gastrointestinal problems might be particularly at risk for such reactions.
        \n\nTaking blackberry leaf or root preparations with food may reduce risk of gastrointestinal problems in some people.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="chives_content"><font size="14"><b>Chives (Allium schoenoprasum)</b>
     Chives are a perennial member of the onion family that sport beautiful edible flowers.
        \n\nPlus, they\’re a wonderful companion plant that helps deter pests.

        \n\nCommon chives consist of clumps of small, slender bulbs that produce thin, tubular, blue-green leaves reaching 10-15 inches in height.
        \n\nThe edible, flavorful flowers may be white, pink, purple, or red, depending on variety. They can be grown in zones 3 to 9.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Chives</b></font>

         \nChives are extremely rich in flavonoid antioxidants, which contribute to most of the benefits.
        \n\nThese antioxidants help fight cancer, improve heart health, and can even fight inflammation.
        \n\nThey also detoxify the body and boost skin health. And the fiber in them can help ease the digestive process.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nSince chives have a milder flavor, they\'re perfect to add to soups, dips, mashed or baked potatoes, fish, seafood dishes and omelets.
        \nn\nHeat destroys their delicate flavor, so add chives to dishes at the last minute.
        \n\nTo maximize their taste, thinly slice, chop or snip with kitchen shears before using.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nTaking too much chive can cause an upset stomach.
        \n\nWhen applied to the skin: There isn\'t enough reliable information to know if chive is safe when applied to the skin.
        \n\nIt might cause side effects such as allergic skin reactions in some people.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="goji_berry_content"><font size="14"><b>Goji_berry (Lycium barbarum)</b>
      is native to Asia, and people in Asia have been using this brightly colored fruit for more than 2,000 years as a medicinal herb and food supplement.
        \n\nGoji berries are widely available for purchase in health food stores and online.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Goji berry</b></font>

         \nGoji berries are rich in nutrients. Some early studies using goji berry juice found possible benefits that included:

        \n\n1. A feeling of well-being and calmness
        \n2. Better athletic performance
        \n3. Better sleep
        \n4. Weight loss
        \n5. A boost to your immune system
        \n6. Higher antioxidant levels

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nRaw: First and foremost, eat them raw! A small handful a day will do.
        \n\nJuice: Goji berries are also available in juice form. Down to Earth carries 100\% Goji Juice without any added sugar, or color.
        \n\nTea: Goji berries can be used to brew in a tea. You can add a handful of goji berries to a big glass of hot or cold water (or herb tea) and let sit and hydrate for 5 to 10 minutes. They become plump and juicy. You can drink the tea and eat the hydrated berries which are loaded with antioxidants.
        \n\nSmoothies: Soak a handful of goji berries in water for 10 minutes. Once they are plump and juicy, add them to your favorite smoothie. It won’t make much of a change to the taste or consistency of your smoothie.
        \n\nTrail Mix: You can also add goji berries to your favorite trail mix. Or, make your own by mixing your favorite nuts and dried fruit with some goji berries. Kids like it when you add some chocolate or peanut butter chips to the goji trail mix.
        \n\nCereal: Just like raisins, add some goji berries to your hot or cold cereals in the morning.
        \n\nMuffins and Scones: Add goji berries to muffins or scones just as you would raisins.
        \n\nGoji Energy Bars: Blend a handful of goji berries together with cup of walnuts, ½ cup almonds, and 5-6 dates in a food processor. Roll the mix into balls or spread in a deep pan to make bars.
        \n\nAdd to Soups: This has been a common use of goji berries in Chinese cuisine for thousands of years.



    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nFresh and dry goji berries do not usually cause any side effects or adverse reactions in healthy people.
        \n\nGoji berry supplements have been shown to be safe for most people when consumed for up to 3 months, with only rare side effects, such as allergic reactions and sensitivity to sunlight.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="gooseberry_content"><font size="14"><b>Gooseberry (Ribes uva-crispa)</b>
     is a species of flowering shrub in the currant family, Grossulariaceae. It is native to Europe, the Caucasus and northern Africa.
        \n\nGooseberry bushes produce an edible fruit and are grown on both a commercial and domestic basis.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Gooseberry</b></font>

         \n1. Highly nutritious
        \n2. High in fiber and low in calories
        \n3. Rich in antioxidants
        \n4. May help control blood sugar
        \n5. May protect your brain
        \n6. May have anticancer effects
        \n7. Good for your heart
        \n8. Easy to add to your diet

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nGooseberries are often added to drinks and desserts as a compote or purée, as well as being made into jams, chutneys and sauces in savoury dishes.
        \n\nThey pair especially well with other seasonal fruits such as elderflowers and strawberries, along with citrus fruits.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nTannins can cause nausea and even vomiting in people with sensitive stomachs. People with chronic gastrointestinal problems might be particularly at risk for such reactions.
        \n\nTaking blackberry leaf or root preparations with food may reduce risk of gastrointestinal problems in some people.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="juniper_content"><font size="14"><b>Juniper berry (Juniperus communis berries)</b>
     \nA juniper berry is the female seed cone produced by the various species of junipers.
        \n\nIt is not a true berry, but a cone with unusually fleshy and merged scales, which gives it a berry-like appearance.
        \n\nThe cones from a handful of species, especially Juniperus communis, are used as a spice, particularly in European cuisine, and also give gin its distinctive flavour.
        \n\nJuniper berries are among the only spices derived from conifers, along with spruce buds.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Juniper berry</b></font>

         \n1. High in nutrients and powerful plant compounds
        \n2. Provide anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects
        \n3. May have anti-diabetic properties
        \n4. Could promote heart health
        \n5. Antibacterial and antifungal activity

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nBecause of their strong flavor, juniper berries aren\'t eaten on their own like other berries. Rather, they\'re used like a spice or a flavoring for a dish.
        \n\nThe most prevalent way they\'re used is to flavor gin. Other uses for juniper berries include in teas, meat dishes, brines, and in sauerkraut.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nUsing juniper on the skin can cause some side effects including irritation, burning, redness, and swelling. Avoid using it on large skin wounds.
        \n\nTaking juniper by mouth long-term or in a high dose is LIKELY UNSAFE as it can cause kidney problems, seizures, and other serious side effects.
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="lilac_content"><font size="14"><b>Lilac (genus Syringa)</b>
     \nis a genus of 12 currently recognized species of flowering woody plants in the olive family, native to woodland and scrub from southeastern Europe to eastern Asia, and widely and commonly cultivated in temperate areas elsewhere.

        \n\nMany people are aware that lilac blossoms are edible, though they definitely smell much better than they taste.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Juniper berry</b></font>

         \n1. Vermifuge: Lilac essential oil is an effective vermifuge, which means that it helps purge your body of intestinal worms.
        \n2. Antifungal
        \n3. Astringent
        \n4. Febrifuge
        \n5. Eases Anxiety
        \n6. Treats Skin Problems
        \n7. Possible Psychic Effects
        \n8. Antibacterial

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \n1. Sugar them for desserts. Lilacs are edible, so feel free to top your desserts with them.
        \n\n2. Freeze them in ice cubes. If you are hosting a baby or bridal shower, try freezing lilac blooms in ice cubes.
        \n\n3. Make your own lilac honey. Lilacs and honey pair quite well together.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nLilacs do not contain any chemicals or toxins that will poison humans or animals and they do not irritate the skin.
        \n\nLilacs are free of poisons from the tips of their branches to the ends of their roots. In fact, the flowers of the lilac are actually edible.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="mint_content"><font size="14"><b>Mint (Mentha)</b>
     \nis a genus of plants in the family Lamiaceae. The exact distinction between species is unclear; it is estimated that 13 to 24 species exist.
        \n\nHybridization occurs naturally where some species\' ranges overlap. Many hybrids and cultivars are known.
        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of White clover</b></font>

        \n1. Rich in Nutrients
        \n2. May Improve Irritable Bowel Syndrome
        \n3. May Help Relieve Indigestion
        \n4. Could Improve Brain Function
        \n5. May Decrease Breastfeeding Pain
        \n6. Subjectively Improves Cold Symptoms
        \n7. May Mask Bad Breath
        \n8. Easy to Add to Your Diet.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \n1. Eating fresh or dried leaves: Used to treat bad breath.
        \n2. Inhaling essential oils: May improve brain function and cold symptoms.
        \n3. Applying it to the skin: Used to reduce nipple pain from breastfeeding.
        \n4. Taking capsules with food: May help treat IBS and indigestion.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nMint is safe for most people and consuming it doesn\'t typically cause side effects. Allergies to mint are uncommon.
        \n\nIn people who are allergic to mint, an interaction with the herb can trigger asthma symptoms.

        \n\nFor this reason, people who are allergic to mint should avoid it completely.
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="mulberry_content"><font size="14"><b>Mulberry (Morus alba)</b>
     \nknown as white mulberry, common mulberry and silkworm mulberry, is a fast-growing, small to medium-sized mulberry tree which grows to 10–20 m tall.
        \n\nIt is generally a short-lived tree with a lifespan comparable to that of humans, although there are some specimens known to be more than 250 years old.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Mulberry</b></font>

         \n1. Improves digestive health
        \n2. Controls blood sugar levels
        \n3. Reduces cancer risk
        \n4. Improves blood circulation
        \n5. Improves immunity
        \n6. Builds bone tissue
        \n7. Promotes brain health
        \n8. Promotes liver health

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nMulberries are best eaten fresh, plucked from the plant.
        \n\nMake sure you don\'t eat the greenish berries as they are still raw – they have a laxative effect.
        \nnEnjoy fresh or frozen mulberries as you would your favorite berries—over porridge, in salads, baked into muffins and cobblers, frozen into sorbet or fruit bars.
        \n\nDon\'t forget about dried mulberries, which are a great anytime snack, but they\'re great in granola and trail mixes too.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nAlthough mulberry leaf has largely been shown to be safe in both human and animal studies, it may lead to side effects in some people.
        \n\nFor example, some people have reported adverse effects, such as diarrhea, nausea, dizziness, bloating, and constipation, when taking supplements \n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="raspberry_content"><font size="14"><b>Raspberry (Rubus idaeus)</b>
     \n is the edible fruit of a multitude of plant species in the genus Rubus of the rose family, most of which are in the subgenus Idaeobatus.
        \n\nThe name also applies to these plants themselves.Raspberries are perennial with woody stems.

        \n\nRaspberries are grown primarily for their fruits. Raspberries are used to eat raw or prepare cakes, jams or stored canned.
        \n\nIn addition to the raspberry fruit, these shrubs also have other edible parts: The tender roots, after thoroughly boiled, are also edible.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Raspberry</b></font>

         \nThey provide potassium, essential to heart function, and proven to lower blood pressure.
        \n\nThe omega-3 fatty acids in raspberries can help prevent stroke and heart disease.
        \n\nThey also contain a mineral called manganese, which is necessary for healthy bones and skin and helps regulate blood sugar.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nRaspberries are grown primarily for their fruits. Raspberries are used to eat raw or prepare cakes, jams or stored canned.
        \n\nIn addition to the raspberry fruit, these shrubs also have other edible parts: The tender roots, after thoroughly boiled, are also edible.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nNo side effects from taking red raspberry have been reported.
        \n\nHowever, there have been reports of raspberries contaminated with bacteria and viruses, causing symptoms like nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="redcurrant_content"><font size="14"><b>Redcurrant (Ribes rubrum)</b>
     \n is a member of the genus Ribes in the gooseberry family.It is native to western Europe.
        \n\nThe species is widely cultivated and has escaped into the wild in many regions.

        \n\n Red currants are hardy shrubs that produce tender, tart red berries in late June to mid-July.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Raspberry</b></font>

        \nRed or black, the currant is a good vitamin source. The red currant must be preferably ripe and fresh, so as to preserve all its nutritional value.
        \n\nIts content in flavonoids and vitamin B helps to fortify the capillaries, protecting the body tissues and preventing arteriosclerosis, apoplexy and diabetes.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nFresh currants can be used like blueberries, and somewhat like blackberries or raspberries, in tarts and pies, and other desserts, such as sorbets and puddings.
        \n\nUse them fresh in fruit salads, particularly berry mixes, or to garnish desserts with their pretty color.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nWhen taken by mouth Black currant is LIKELY SAFE when used as food, or when black currant berry, juice, extracts, or seed oil is used appropriately as medicine.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="rhubarb_content"><font size="14"><b>Redcurrant (Rheum rhabarbarum)</b>
     \nRhubarb is a spring vegetable, one of the few that is still truly seasonal.
        \n\nThe edible part of this perennial plant is the vibrant pink stalk, which is almost always cooked with lots of sugar because it is very sour.

        \n\nRhubarb is the fleshy, edible stalks of species and hybrids of Rheum in the family Polygonaceae, which are cooked and used for food.

        \n\n Red currants are hardy shrubs that produce tender, tart red berries in late June to mid-July.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Raspberry</b></font>

         \nNutrition. Rhubarb is rich in antioxidants, particularly anthocyanins (which give it its red color) and proanthocyanidins.
        \n\nThese antioxidants have anti-bacterial, anti-inflammatory, and anti-cancer properties, which help protect you from many health-related issues such as heart disease, cancer, and diabetes.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nFresh currants can be used like blueberries, and somewhat like blackberries or raspberries, in tarts and pies, and other desserts, such as sorbets and puddings.
        \n\nUse them fresh in fruit salads, particularly berry mixes, or to garnish desserts with their pretty color.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nWhen taken by mouth Black currant is LIKELY SAFE when used as food, or when black currant berry, juice, extracts, or seed oil is used appropriately as medicine.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="rosehip_content"><font size="14"><b>Rose hip (Rosa canina L.)</b>
     \nis the part of the rose flower just below the petals that contains the rose plant seeds. It has been used for osteoarthritis and contains vitamin C.

        \n\nThe rose hip or rosehip, also called rose haw and rose hep, is the accessory fruit of the various species of rose plant.
        \n\nIt is typically red to orange, but ranges from dark purple to black in some species.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Raspberry</b></font>

         \n1. May Help Prevent Cancer And Other Chronic Diseases
        \n2. Lower Cholesterol
        \n3. Additional Vitamin C Benefits
        \n4. Help Prevent Rheumatoid Arthritis
        \n5. Can Help Manage Diabetes
        \n6. Good For The Heart
        \n7. Treat Inflammation
        \n8. Aid Digestion
        \n9. Regulate Blood Pressure
        \10. Improve Skin Health
        \11. Enhance Blood Circulation
        12. Improve Kidney Health

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nWays to Use Rose Hips. Use them in tea (fresh or dried), on their own or mixed with other herbs.
        \n\nRose hips pair exceptionally well with citrus, lemongrass, other berries, dried apples, and honey.
        \n\nUse a couple teaspoons or one tablespoon of rosehips per cup of water for tea.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nRose hip can cause some side effects such as nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, heartburn, stomach cramps, fatigue, headache, inability to sleep, and others.
        \n\nInhaling rose hip dust can cause an allergic reaction in some people.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="white_clover_content"><font size="14"><b>White clover (Trifolium repens)</b>
     \nis a herbaceous perennial plant in the bean family Fabaceae.
        \n\nIt is native to Europe, including the British Isles, and central Asia and is one of the most widely cultivated types of clover.

        \n\nWhite clover is a low-growing perennial commonly found in lawns. People are generally unaware of its presence until it puts out small, white flowers, in late spring, which attract bees.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of White clover</b></font>

         \nA white clover infusion can boost the immune system and treat fever, coughs, and colds.
        \n\nIt\'s also good for treating common cold symptoms, such as congestion and headaches.
        \n\nWhite clover herbal tea could treat rheumatic aches and joint pain too.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nUse the leaves raw in salads or dry for baked goods later.
        \n\nThe flowers make a delicious tea and can be used dried or fresh.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nWhite clover is known to cause certain adverse effects and, hence, it is advisable that you use it with caution. For instance, this plant is said to cause some troubles for grazing animals.
        \n\nThese problems may be related to the climatic conditions where the plant is growing.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>


</resources>