<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string name="echinacea_content"><font size="14"><b>Echinacea</b>, also called purple coneflower, is one of the most popular herbs worldwide.
        \nThey’re native to North America where they grow in prairies and open, wooded areas.
        \n\nBoth the plant’s upper parts and roots are used in tablets, tinctures, extracts and teas.
    \n\nEchinacea plants contain an impressive variety of active compounds, such as caffeic acid, alkamides, phenolic acids, rosmarinic acid, polyacetylenes and many more.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits</b></font>
        \n1. May lower blood sugar levels.
        \n2. May reduce feelings of anxiety.
        \n3. Anti-inflammatory properties.
        \n4. May help treat skin concerns.
        \n5. May offer protection against cancer.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nAdult. For general immune system stimulation, during colds, flu, upper respiratory tract infections, or bladder infections, take echinacea 3 times a day until you feel better, but not for more than 10 days.
    DO NOT take echinacea on an empty stomach.
    Instead, take it with food or a large glass of water.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nThere have been cases where people experienced side effects, such as:
    \n1. Rashes
    \n2. Itchy skin
    \n3. Hives
    \n4. Swelling
    \n5. Stomach pain
    \n6. Nausea

    \n\nHowever, these side effects are more common among people with allergies to other flowers, such as daisies, chrysanthemums, marigolds, ragweed and more.
As echinacea appears to stimulate the immune system, people with autoimmune disorders or people taking immunosuppressive drugs should avoid it or consult their doctors first.\n\n
    </font>
</string>

    <string name="elderberry_content"><font size="14"><b>Elderberry</b> is the dark purple berry of the European or black elder tree, which grows in the warmer parts of Europe, North America, Asia, and Northern Africa.
        \n\nThe berries and flowers of elderberry are packed with antioxidants and vitamins that may boost your immune system.

         <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits</b></font>
        \nThe berries and flowers of elderberry are packed with antioxidants and vitamins that may boost your immune system.
        They could help tame inflammation, lessen stress, and help protect your heart, too.
        Some experts recommend elderberry to help prevent and ease cold and flu symptoms.
        \n\nIt’s also been used as a treatment for:
        \n1. Constipation
        \n2. Joint and muscle pain
        \n3. Infections that affect how you breathe
        \n4. Headaches
        \n5. Fever
        \n6. Kidney problems
        \n7. Epilepsy
        \n8. HIV and AIDS

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \n<b>Do not eat raw elderberries as they can be poisonous.</b>
        \n\nHowever, there are various ways to prepare elderberries.
        \n\nTo make elderberry syrup:
        \n1. remove the stalks
        \n2. cook the berries in water and sugar
        \n3. strain
        \n4. boil the liquid to reduce it until it takes on a syrup-like consistency
        \n\nPeople can then drizzle the syrup over plain yogurt or add it to a smoothie.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nSide effects</b></font>
        \nPeople can eat elderflowers raw or cooked. However, raw elderberries, as well as the seeds, leaves, and bark of the tree, contain a toxic substance.
        Eating or drinking raw elderberries or another toxic part of the plant can lead to nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea.\n\n
        </font>
    </string>

        <string name="ginger_content"><font size="14"><b>Ginger</b>(Zingiber officinale) is a plant native to Asia.
        The ginger spice comes from the roots of the plant. It\'s used as a food flavoring and medicine.

        \n\nGinger contains chemicals that might reduce nausea and swelling.
        These chemicals seem to work in the stomach and intestines,
        but they might also help the brain and nervous system to control nausea.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of ginger</b></font>
        \n1. Fight germs
        \n2. Keeps your mouth healthy
        \n3. Calms nausea
        \n4. Soothes sore muscles
        \n5. Eases arthritis symptoms
        \n6. Curbs cancer growth
        \n7. Lowers blood sugar
        \n8. Ease period pain
        \n9. Lowers cholesterol
        \n10. Relieves Indigestion

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
            \n1. Ginger pairs wonderfully with bananas (they are distant relatives), so add grated fresh ginger to banana bread or muffins.
            \n\n2. Ginger also likes apples, so add it to applesauce and apple pie. Or combine it with apples and sugar and simmer to make a compote for topping pancakes.
            \n\n3. Substitute grated fresh ginger for some or all of the powdered ginger called for in your favorite gingerbread recipe.
            \n\n4. In Yemen, ginger is added to coffee. Give it a shot, but be sure to have sugar, cream and maybe a shot of cinnamon nearby.
            \n\n5. Make ginger ale by combining freshly grated ginger, simple syrup (or agave syrup) and seltzer water. A shot of lemon juice is nice, too.
            \n\n6. Combine grated ginger with orange juice and honey for basting a roast chicken or turkey.
            \n\n7. Simmer cubed butternut squash, chopped carrots and garlic in chicken broth. Add fresh ginger, salt and pepper, then puree for a delicious soup.
            \n\n8. Combine ginger, soy sauce, rice vinegar, garlic and sesame oil for a killer marinade for beef (especially thinly sliced steaks).

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nSide effects</b></font>
            \nIt can cause mild side effects including heartburn, diarrhea, burping, and general stomach discomfort.
            Taking higher doses of 5 grams daily increases the risk for side effects.
            When applied to the skin: Ginger is possibly safe when used short-term.
            It might cause skin irritation for some people.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="ginkgo_content"><font size="14"><b>Ginger biloba</b>, or maidenhair, is a tree native to China that has been grown for thousands of years for a variety of uses.
    \n\nWhile its leaves and seeds are often used in traditional Chinese medicine, modern research primarily focuses on ginkgo extract, which is made from the leaves.

    \n\nGinkgo supplements are associated with several health claims and uses, most of which focus on brain function and blood circulation.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of ginkgo biloba</b></font>
        \n1. Contains Powerful Antioxidants
        \n2. Can Help Fight Inflammation
        \n3. Improves Circulation and Heart Health
        \n4. Reduces Symptoms of Psychiatric Disorders and Dementia
        \n5. Improves Brain Function and Well-Being
        \n6. Can Reduce Anxiety
        \n7. Can Treat Depression
        \n8. Can Support Vision and Eye Health
        \n9. Can Treat Headaches and Migraines
        \n10. Can Improve Asthma and COPD Symptoms

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nTo make a tea from the leaves of your tree, pick green leaves in late summer.
        You can then use 1 tablespoon of fresh leaves in one cup of boiling water to make a tea.
        Add a sweetener to it if you wish.
        Alternatively you can shade-dry leaves, preferably on a screen (so there is good air circulation all round).\n\n

        <font size ="18"><b>\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nFor most adults, the risk associated with taking ginkgo is relatively low, but there are cases in which ginkgo could cause serious harm.
        \n\nIf you are allergic to plants that contain alkylphenols or taking certain medications, you should not take ginkgo.
        \n\nPossible side effects include:
        \n1. Nausea
        \n2. Diarrhea
        \n3. Dizziness
        \n4. Headaches
        \n5. Stomach pain
        \n5. Rash/allergic reaction

        \n\nGinkgo has the potential to interact unfavorably with certain medications. Some interactions could increase the risk of bleeding.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="ginseng_content"><font size="14"><b>Ginseng</b> has been used in traditional Chinese medicine for centuries.
        \n\nThis slow-growing, short plant with fleshy roots can be classified three ways, depending on how long it is grown: fresh, white or red.
        \n\nFresh ginseng is harvested before 4 years, while white ginseng is harvested between 4–6 years and red ginseng is harvested after 6 or more years.
        \n\nAmerican and Asian ginseng vary in their concentration of active compounds and effects on the body.
        It is believed that American ginseng works as a relaxing agent, whereas the Asian variety has an invigorating effect.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of ginseng</b></font>
        \n1. Potent Antioxidant That May Reduce Inflammation
        \n2. May Benefit Brain Function
        \n3. Could Improve Erectile Dysfunction
        \n4. May Boost the Immune System
        \n5. May Have Potential Benefits Against Cancer
        \n6. May Fight Tiredness and Increase Energy Levels
        \n7. Could Lower Blood Sugar

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nIt can be eaten raw or you can lightly steam it to soften it. It can also be stewed in water to make a tea.
        To do this, just add hot water to freshly sliced ginseng and let it steep for several minutes.
        Ginseng can be added to various recipes like soups and stir-fries, too.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nIt has been reported to cause nervousness and insomnia.
        Long-term use or high doses of ginseng may lead to headaches, dizziness, stomach upset, and other symptoms.
        \n\nWomen who use ginseng regularly may experience menstrual changes.
        There have also been reports of allergic reactions to ginseng.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="st_johns_wort_content"><font size="14"><b>St. John\'s Wort (Hypericum perforatum)</b>,
        a plant that grows in the wild, has been used for centuries for mental health conditions.
        It\’s widely prescribed for depression in Europe.
        \n\nSt. John\'s wort is available in dietary supplements in the US.
        But France has banned its use in products because of drug interaction concerns.
        In other countries, St. John\'s wort is only available with a prescription.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of St. John\'s Wort</b></font>
        \nReduction in symptoms of depression.
         \nReduction in menopausal symptoms.
         \nAssistance with wound healing (when applied to the skin as a lotion)

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nJohn\'s wort is most often taken in liquid or capsules.
        \nThe dried herb may also be used as a tea.
        \n\nThe most common dose used in studies has been 300 milligrams, three times a day as a standardized extract.
        Preparations in the U.S. have varied amounts in them.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nCombining St. John\’s wort with certain antidepressants can lead to a potentially life-threatening increase of serotonin, a brain chemical targeted by antidepressants.
        \n\nSymptoms occur within minutes to hours, and may include agitation, diarrhea, fast heartbeat, high blood pressure, hallucinations, increased body temperature, and more.
        \n\nThere are case reports of St. John\’s wort having dangerous side effects, such as worsening of psychotic symptoms in people with bipolar disorder or schizophrenia.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="turmeric_content"><font size="14"><b>Turmeric</b>
        , a plant in the ginger family, is native to Southeast Asia and is grown commercially in that region, primarily in India.
        \nIts rhizome (underground stem) is used as a culinary spice and traditional medicine.
        \n\nTurmeric is a natural herb that is commonly used as a spice in a wide variety of food.
        \n\nIt is a plant that is originally from India.
        \nTurmeric is also called curcumin, which is the active ingredient in the spice.
        \nWhen used as a spice in food, turmeric powder is yellow in color.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Turmeric</b></font>
        \n1. Turmeric contains bioactive compounds with medicinal properties
        \n2. Curcumin is a natural anti-inflammatory compound
        \n3. Turmeric can increase the antioxidant capacity of the body
        \n4. Curcumin can boost brain-derived neurotrophic factor
        \n5. Curcumin may lower your risk of heart disease
        \n6. Turmeric may help prevent cancer
        \n7. Curcumin may be useful in treating Alzheimer\’s disease
        \n8. Arthritis patients respond well to curcumin supplements
        \n9. Curcumin has benefits against depression
        \n10. Curcumin may help delay aging and fight age-related chronic diseases

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nA person can brew turmeric tea using pure turmeric powder or grated or ground, dried turmeric.
        \n\nFermented turmeric preparations, commonly sold as tea products, claim to have higher concentrations of biologically available, or absorbable, curcumin.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nCurcumin is generally safe to consume.
        However, in rare cases, consuming too much may lead to symptoms such as diarrhea, yellow stool, rash, nausea, and headaches.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="valerian_content"><font size="14"><b>Valerian (Valeriana officinalis)</b>
         is an herb native to Europe and parts of Asia. Valerian root has a long history of use as a sedative.
        \n\nIn the summer when the mature plant may have a height of 1.5 metres, it bears sweetly scented pink or white flowers that attract many fly species, especially hoverflies of the genus Eristalis.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Valerian root</b></font>
        \nAlternative healthcare providers believe that valerian root can treat a variety of health conditions, including insomnia, anxiety, headaches, digestive problems, menopause symptoms, and post-exercise muscle pain and fatigue.
        The evidence supporting these claims is generally mixed.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nBased on the available research, take 300 to 600 milligrams (mg) of valerian root 30 minutes to two hours before bedtime.
        \n\nThis is best for insomnia or sleep trouble.
        \n\nFor tea, soak 2 to 3 grams of dried herbal valerian root in 1 cup of hot water for 10 to 15 minutes.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nMost clinical studies have shown that valerian root is well-tolerated and safe for short-term use.
        \n\nSide effects, if any, tend to be mild and may include headache, dizziness, itchiness, upset stomach, dry mouth, vivid dreams, and daytime drowsiness.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

</resources>