<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="anise_content"><font size="14"><b>Anise hyssop (Agastache foeniculum)</b>
         commonly called anise hyssop, blue giant hyssop, Fragrant giant hyssop, or the lavender giant hyssop, is a species of perennial plant in the mint family.
        \n\nThis plant is native to much of north-central and northern North America, notably the Great Plains and other prairies.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Anise hyssop</b></font>
        \nInfused in tea, anise hyssop can be used to relieve congestion, acting as an expectorant (clearing mucus from lungs and airways).
        \n\nA cold-infusion can be used to relieve chest pains caused by excessive coughing, and mixed with licorice, it can be used to treat respiratory infections and bronchitis.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nAnise hyssop has a long history of use. Leaves can be used as a seasoning, dried for use in tea, used fresh in salads, or made into jellies.
        \n\nAs leaves maintain their scent well when dried, anise hyssop can also be used in potpourri.
        \n\nHarvested fresh, leaves can be added to summer pasta dishes or cold vegetable soups.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \n1. May Trigger Mint Allergies
        \n2. May Trigger Seizures
        \n3. May Cause Miscarriages

        \n\nNo studies have been done on hyssop to find the safe maximum serving amount.
        \n\nIt appears that the amount normally found in food is generally safe to consume, but large amounts of hyssop or hyssop extract may cause health problems.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="borage_content"><font size="14"><b>Borage (Borago officinalis)</b>
         also known as a starflower, is an annual herb in the flowering plant family Boraginaceae.
        \n\nIt is native to the Mediterranean region, and has naturalized in many other locales.

        \nnBorage is a plant. Its flowers and leaves, as well as the oil from its seeds are used as medicine.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Borage</b></font>
        \nBorage flower and leaves are used for fever, cough, and depression.
        \n\nBorage is also used for a hormone problem called adrenal insufficiency, for \"blood purification,\" to increase urine flow, to prevent inflammation of the lungs, as a sedative, and to promote sweating.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nIn traditional medicine, borage is used as a sedative and a diuretic, and as a treatment for seizures and kidney disease. The leaves are often used as dried herbs or tea.
        \n\nToday, fresh borage is eaten and used as a garnish or in drinks.
        \n\nThe seeds are also pressed to make borage seed oil, which is used as a supplement.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nBorage seed oil is POSSIBLY SAFE when taken by mouth or applied to the skin appropriately.

        \n\nBorage seed oil is LIKELY UNSAFE when products containing a dangerous chemicals called pyrrolizidine alkaloids (PAs) are taken by mouth.
        Borage plant parts including the leaf, flower, and seed can contain PAs.
        \n\nPAs can damage the liver or cause cancer, especially when used in high doses or for a long time.
        \n\nOnly use products that are certified and labeled PA-free.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="epazote_content"><font size="14"><b>Epazote (Dysphania ambrosioides)</b>
         Dysphania ambrosioides, formerly Chenopodium ambrosioides, known as Jesuit\'s tea, Mexican-tea, payqu, epazote, mastruz, or herba sanctæ Mariæ, is an annual or short-lived perennial herb native to Central America, South America, and southern Mexico.

        \n\nEpazote has a strong taste and aroma, so not everyone takes to it right away. It can be somewhat of an acquired taste, but it adds a wonderful rustic layer of flavor to many dishes.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Epazote</b></font>
        \nSome of the health benefits of epazote may include its ability to reduce flatulence, reduce respiratory conditions, eliminate parasites, improve the metabolism, protect the immune system, help with weight loss efforts, heal wounds, and reduce menstrual discomfort.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nEpazote is most frequently used to season frijoles de la olla (pot beans), especially when they are black beans.
        \n\nIt is also common in stews and rustic dishes made with mushrooms or corn.
        \n\nA sprig of the herb is often used inside a quesadilla made with corn tortillas.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nIt can irritate the skin, mouth, throat, and lining of the stomach and intestines.
        \n\nIt can also cause vomiting, headache, dizziness, kidney and liver damage, temporary deafness, convulsions, paralysis, and death. Chenopodium oil can explode if heated or mixed with acids.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="feverfew_content"><font size="14"><b>Feverfew (Tanacetum parthenium)</b>
         is a flowering plant in the daisy family, Asteraceae. It may be grown as an ornament, and may be identified by its synonyms, Chrysanthemum parthenium and Pyrethrum parthenium.

        \n\nFeverfew is a plant native to Asia Minor and the Balkans. Feverfew dried leaves, fresh leaves, and extracts are used in medicine.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Feverfew</b></font>
        \nFeverfew may reduce painful inflammation due to arthritis. Feverfew may help bring on uterine contractions to reduce the length of labor.
        \n\nIt may aid in starting menstrual periods and treating menstrual pain.
        \n\nFeverfew may relieve colitis and soothe insect bites.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nDosing. Feverfew generally is given for migraine at a daily dose of 50 to 150 mg of dried leaves, 2.5 fresh leaves with or after food, or 5 to 20 drops of a 1:5, 25% ethanol tincture.
        \n\nAn optimal dose of feverfew has not been established.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nNo serious side effects have been reported from feverfew use.
        \n\nSide effects can include nausea, digestive problems, and bloating; if the fresh leaves are chewed, sores and irritation of the mouth may occur.
        \n\nPeople who are sensitive to ragweed and related plants may experience allergic reactions to feverfew.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="french_sorrel_content"><font size="14"><b>French sorrel (Rumex scutatus)</b>
         is a plant in the buckwheat family, used as a culinary herb.
        \n\nIts common names include French sorrel, buckler sorrel, shield-leaf sorrel, and sometimes the culinary name \"green-sauce\".
        \n\nAs a culinary herb, it is used in salads, soups, and sauces.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of French sorrel</b></font>
        \nSorrel is especially high in vitamin C, a water-soluble vitamin that fights inflammation and plays a key role in immune function.
        \n\nIt\'s also high in fiber, which can promote regularity, increase feelings of fullness, and help stabilize blood sugar levels.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nSorrel falls straight between herbs and greens.
        \n\nUse it as a leafy herb, like parsley or basil or mint, chopping it up to use in marinades and dressings, or stirring it into soups or casseroles for a bit of fresh flavor. Or, use it as a green, ripping the tender leaves into salads and stir-fries.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nIn larger doses, sorrel can cause damage to the kidneys, liver, and digestive organs.
        \n\nSorrel is POSSIBLY UNSAFE when taken in large amounts, since it might increase the risk of developing kidney stones.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="lettuce_leaf_basil_content"><font size="14"><b>Lettuce leaf basil (Perilla frutescens var. crispa)</b>
          is a large-leaf variety of Ocimum basilicum. The large, crinkled leaves, which grow on the short, wide plant, are sweet, but not as strong as other sweet basils.
        \n\nThis makes them particularly suitable for tossing into salads or wrapping fish, chicken or a rice stuffing for grilling.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Lettuce leaf basil</b></font>
        \n1. Good For Digestion
        \n2. Anti-inflammatory
        \n3. Fights free radical activity
        \n4. Fights Depression
        \n5. Skin Benefits
        \n6. Diabetes Management
        \n7. Supports Liver Function and Helps Detoxify the Body
        \n8. Promote healthy gut
        \n9. Heals An Upset Tummy

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nPlant it near those susceptible to insect marauders and throughout the annual or cutting garden.
        \n\nThe enormous basil leaves of Lettuce Leaf basil are perfect for using in place of lettuce for fresh wraps, stuffing, layering in lasagna, and for making an abundance of pesto.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nBasil contains a chemical, estragole, which has caused liver cancer in laboratory mice.
        \n\nBleeding disorders: Basil oils and extracts might slow blood clotting and increase the risk of bleeding in people with bleeding disorders.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="lovage_content"><font size="14"><b>Lovage (Levisticum officinale)</b>
          is a tall perennial plant, the sole species in the genus Levisticum in the family Apiaceae, subfamily Apioideae.
        \n\nIt has been long cultivated in Europe, the leaves being used as a herb, the roots as a vegetable, and the seeds as a spice, especially in southern European cuisine.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Lettuce leaf basil</b></font>
        \nLovage is probably best known as a digestive aid, relieving flatulence and other stomach discomfort.
        \n\nIn addition to helping digestion, lovage was commonly used to strengthen the heart and as a respiratory aid.
        \n\nIt was also useful as a diuretic, to treat kidney stones and as a blood purifier.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nAdd leaves to a mix of salad greens or let wilt in soups and stocks.
        \n\nChop and use in place of parsley in chicken and tuna salad or a batch of fresh tomato salsa.
        \n\nPuree leaves and stalks into a morning smoothie (or Bloody Mary). Add celery seeds to marinades, soups, creamy dips, chili and potato salad.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nLovage is POSSIBLY SAFE for most people. It might increase sensitivity to the sun, especially with long-term use.
        \n\nThis might put you at greater risk for rashes from the sun, sunburns, and skin cancer.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="marsh_mallow_content"><font size="14"><b>Marsh mallow (Althaea officinalis)</b>
         the marsh mallow or marshmallow, is a species of flowering plant indigenous to Europe, Western Asia and North Africa, which is used in herbalism and as an ornamental plant.

        \n\nMarsh-mallow is a wonderful food source. The entire plant is edible and each part offers tremendous health benefits.

        \n\nThe leaves and the root are sometimes used to make medicine.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Marsh mallow</b></font>
        \nMarshmallow is sometimes used to form a protective layer on the skin and lining of the digestive tract. It also contains chemicals that might decrease cough and fight infections.
        \n\nDon\'t confuse marshmallow with the mallow (Malva sylvestris) flower and leaf.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nTo treat dry mouth, people can use marshmallow root lozenges.
        \n\nIt is important to allow the lozenge to dissolve slowly in the mouth and to avoid chewing it.
        \n\nAlternatively, people can make an herbal tea using either marshmallow root tea bags or the dried herb in a tea strainer and drink 2 to 3 cups daily.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nIt has no reported side effects. It appears to be safe for use during pregnancy and breastfeeding, although you should check with your doctor before taking it.
        \n\nOne study suggests marshmallow may lower blood sugar levels.
        \n\nSo people with diabetes should talk to their doctors before taking marshmallow.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="saffron_content"><font size="14"><b>Saffron (Crocus sativus)</b>
          is a spice derived from the flower of Crocus sativus, commonly known as the \"saffron crocus\".
        \n\nThe vivid crimson stigma and styles, called threads, are collected and dried for use mainly as a seasoning and colouring agent in food.
        \n\nSaffron has long been the world\'s costliest spice by weight.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Marsh mallow</b></font>
        \n1. 1. A powerful antioxidant
        \n2. May improve mood and treat depressive symptoms
        \n3. May have cancer-fighting properties
        \n4. May reduce PMS symptoms
        \n5. May act as an aphrodisiac
        \n6. May reduce appetite and aid weight loss
        \n7. May reduce heart disease risk factors.
        \n8. May lower blood sugar levels.
        \n9. May improve eyesight in adults with age-related macular degeneration (AMD).
        \n10. May improve memory in adults with Alzheimer’s disease.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nOne of the most common ways of adding saffron to a dish is to first steep it in water, like a tea.
        \n\nThis is an easy method that requires nothing more than time and heat.
        \n\nStart by roughly crumpling the stamens between my fingertips before covering them with a couple of tablespoons of warm water or milk.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nSome common side effects include drowsiness, stomach problems, and nausea or vomiting.
        \n\nAllergic reactions are also possible.
        \n\nTaking large amounts of saffron by mouth is possibly unsafe. High doses of 5 grams or more can cause poisoning.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="stevia_content"><font size="14"><b>Stevia (Stevia rebaudiana)</b>
          is a natural sweetener and sugar substitute derived from the leaves of the plant species Stevia rebaudiana, native to Brazil and Paraguay.

        \n\nStevia is a sugar substitute made from the leaves of the stevia plant. It\'s about 100 to 300 times sweeter than table sugar, but it has no carbohydrates.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Stevia</b></font>
        \nStevia is often touted as a safe and healthy sugar substitute that can sweeten up foods without the negative health effects linked to refined sugar.
        \n\nIt\'s also associated with several impressive health benefits, such as reduced calorie intake, blood sugar levels, and risk of cavities

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nYou can use stevia like you would table sugar.
        \n\nSweeten a drink with it or sprinkle it on your cereal.
        \n\nYou can also cook with it. Each brand has its own sugar-to-stevia ratio, so check the package before you measure out sweetener. It can cause a bitter aftertaste if you use too much.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nWhen taken by mouth: Certain chemicals in stevia, including stevioside and rebaudioside A, are likely safe when used as a food sweetener.
        \n\nSide effects might include bloating, nausea, dizziness, and numbness.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="sweet_cicely_content"><font size="14"><b>Sweet cicely (Myrrhis odorata)</b>
          , myrrh, garden myrrh, and sweet chervil, is a herbaceous perennial plant belonging to the celery family Apiaceae. It is the only species in the genus Myrrhis.

        \n\nSweet Cicely is a special plant.  Tolerant if not adoring of the shadier nooks in our gardens, this beautiful plant comes up reliably early in the year with a plume of foliage quite like ferns.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Sweet cicely</b></font>

        \nSweet cicely is an herb. It is used to make medicine.
        \n\nPeople take sweet cicely as a tea or tonic for asthma and other breathing problems, cough, digestion problems, chest and throat complaints, and urinary tract disorders.
        \n\nIt is also used as a \“blood purifier.\”

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nYou can also cook the leaves like spinach, or add fresh leaves to salads, soups or omelets.
        \n\nThe stalks can be used much like celery, while the roots can be boiled or eaten raw. Many people say sweet cicely roots make flavorful wine

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nThere isn\'t enough information available to know if sweet cicely is safe or what the possible side effects might be.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="tulsi_content"><font size="14"><b>Tulsi (Ocimum tenuiflorum)</b>
           commonly known as holy basil, tulsi or tulasi, is an aromatic perennial plant in the family Lamiaceae.

        \n\nIt is native to the Indian subcontinent and widespread as a cultivated plant throughout the Southeast Asian tropics.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Tulsi</b></font>

        \n1. Reduce stress and anxiety
        \n2. Protect against infection and treat wounds
        \n3. Lower your blood sugar
        \n4. Lower your cholesterol
        \n5. Ease inflammation and joint pain
        \n6. Natural Immunity Booster
        \n7. Reduces Fever (antipyretic) and Pain(analgesic)
        \n8. Treatment of Eczema

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nConsume Tulsi leaves raw, plucked fresh from the plant, add it your tea or make kadha out of it.
        \n\nTulsi tea\: To make tulsi tea, boil 1 cup of water and pour it over 1 tsp of fresh tulsi leaves, 1\/2 tsp of dried tulsi leaves or 1\/3 tsp of tulsi powder. Cover the water in a pot or mug and let it seep for 15\-20 minutes. Then strain the leaves, add honey if desired and enjoy.
        \n\nTulsi powders and supplements are also available in the market for consumption.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nTulsi may affect the reproductive capacity of women who are trying to conceive.
        \n\nSome people experience nausea or diarrhoea when they first add tulsi tea to their diet, so it is best to start with small quantities and increase your consumption over time.
        \n\nTulsi may lower blood sugar and should be used with caution in people who have diabetes and are on blood\-sugar\-lowering medication.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

</resources>