<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Hervmed2</string>

    <string name="chamomile_content"><b>Chamomile</b> (American English) or camomile (British English; see spelling differences) (/ˈkæməmaɪl, -miːl/ <i>KAM-ə-myle</i> or <i>KAM-ə-meel</i>), is the common name for several daisy-like plants of the family Asteraceae.\n\n Two of the species, <i>Matricaria recutita </i>, and  <i>Anthemis nobilis </i> are commonly used to make herbal infusions for beverages.\n\n There is insufficient scientific evidence that consuming chamomile in foods or beverages has any beneficial effect on health.\n\n<b>Benefits and its use</b>\nThe flowers are most often used to make tea, but the leaves may also be dried and used for making tea, medicinal extracts, or topical compresses.
\n\nFor thousands of years, chamomile has been used as a remedy for nausea, diarrhea, constipation, stomach pain, urinary tract infections, wounds, and upper respiratory infections (24Trusted Source).
\n\nThis herb packs over 100 active compounds, many of which are thought to contribute to its numerous benefits (24Trusted Source).\n\n
Several test-tube and animal studies have demonstrated anti-inflammatory, antimicrobial, and antioxidant activity, though insufficient human research is available (25Trusted Source).\n\n
Yet, a few small human studies suggest that chamomile treats diarrhea, emotional disturbances as well as cramping associated with premenstrual syndrome (PMS), and pain and inflammation linked to osteoarthritis (25Trusted Source).
\n\nChamomile is safe for most people but may cause an allergic reaction — especially if you’re allergic to similar plants, such as daisies, ragweed, or marigolds.\n\n</string>



    <string name="borage_content">Also known as a starflower, is an annual herb in the flowering plant family Boraginaceae. It is native to the Mediterranean region, and has naturalized in many other locales.
It grows satisfactorily in gardens in most of Europe, such as Denmark, France, Germany, and the United Kingdom, remaining in the garden from year to year by self-seeding. The leaves are edible and the plant is grown in gardens for that purpose in some parts of Europe.
The plant is also commercially cultivated for borage seed oil extracted from its seeds.
The plant contains pyrrolizidine alkaloids, some of which are hepatotoxic, mutagenic, and carcinogenic (see below under Phytochemistry). \n\n
</string>
</resources>