<resources>

    <string-array name="DidYouKnow">
        <item>If onions make you cry when you chop them, it’s because they give off sulphenic acid, a serious irritant, when you cut them.</item>
        <item>Some believe that oregano also helps ease the process of letting go – so it’s no surprise that a pizza after a break-up is often just the ticket.</item>
        <item>Thyme, a fresh herb with a slight flavor of mint, is often used as a seasoning for fish, chicken or stuffing.</item>
        <item>Rosemary, is a culinary plant with leaves that are similar to needles. Crushing the needles into a recipe gives it an instant pine flavor.</item>
        <item>Oregano is a strong, spicy, fresh tasting herb that is mostly associated with Italian food like pizza and spaghetti sauce.</item>
        <item>Herbs can be grown in the wild, in a garden or flower bed, or even in your house.</item>
        <item>Herbs can be used fresh or dried. Some herbs have a stronger flavor when they are dried, but others have a stronger flavor when fresh.</item>
        <item>Onions are one of the oldest foods known to the human race.</item>
        <item>Sweet potatoes are one of the healthiest foods we can eat, as long as they aren’t covered in sugar and marshmallows.</item>
        <item>The word “herb” comes from the Latin word herba, meaning grass, green stalks, or blades.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="app_name">Hervmed</string>

    <string name="chamomile_content"><font size="14"><b>Chamomile</b> (American English) or camomile (British English; see spelling differences) (/ˈkæməmaɪl, -miːl/ <i>KAM-ə-myle</i> or <i>KAM-ə-meel</i>), is the common name for several daisy-like plants of the family Asteraceae.\n\n Two of the species, <i>Matricaria recutita </i>, and  <i>Anthemis nobilis </i> are commonly used to make herbal infusions for beverages.\n\nThere is insufficient scientific evidence that consuming chamomile in foods or beverages has any beneficial effect on health.</font>
        \n\n<b><font size="18">How to use</font></b>
        \n<font size="14">Infuse chamomile flowers in almond oil. Use the chamomile oil for salads or fish dishes, or mix it in mayonnaise to add flavor to sandwiches.
            Add a few blooms to add color and flavor to a fresh green salad.
            You can also use leaves, although they may have a somewhat bitter flavor.</font>
        \n\n<b><font size="18">Benefits</font></b><font size="14">\nThe flowers are most often used to make tea, but the leaves may also be dried and used for making tea, medicinal extracts, or topical compresses.
\n\nFor thousands of years, chamomile has been used as a remedy for nausea, diarrhea, constipation, stomach pain, urinary tract infections, wounds, and upper respiratory infections.
            \n\nYet, a few small human studies suggest that chamomile treats diarrhea, emotional disturbances as well as cramping associated with premenstrual syndrome (PMS), and pain and inflammation linked to osteoarthritis.\n</font>
    \n<b><font size="18">Side effects</font></b>
    <font size="14">\nChamomile contains a small amount of coumarin, which may have very mild blood thinning effects, but usually just in high doses for long periods of time. Stop using chamomile two weeks before surgery due to concerns about its possible interactions with anesthetic drugs.</font>
    \n\n</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>