<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="chaparral_content"><font size="14"><b>Chaparral (Larrea tridentata)</b>
    is an herb from the creosote bush, a desert shrub native to southern areas of the United States and northern regions of Mexico.
        \n\nIt\'s also called Larrea tridentate, chaparral, and greasewood and has been used as an herbal medicine for centuries.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Chaparral</b></font>

        \nChaparral has been used topically to decrease inflammation, and pain, and promote healing of minor wounds.

        \n\nChaparral is claimed to help treat over 50 ailments, including cancer, arthritis, tuberculosis, skin conditions, and the common cold.
        \n\nIt\’s commonly sold as an oral supplement, essential oil, tea, and homeopathic preparation


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nFor topical use, cloths can be soaked in oil preparations or tea of chaparral and applied several times per day (with heat if helpful) over the affected area.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nWhen taken by mouth: Chaparral is LIKELY UNSAFE. There are several reports of serious poisoning, acute hepatitis, and kidney and liver damage, including kidney and liver failure, in people who have taken chaparral.
        \n\nChaparral can also cause side effects including stomach pain, nausea, diarrhea, weight loss, and fever.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="comfrey_content"><font size="14"><b>Comfrey (Symphytum)</b>
    is a shrub that grows in parts of Europe, Asia, and North America. It can grow up to 5 feet tall.
        \n\nIt produces clusters of purple, blue, and white flowers, and it\'s famous for its long, slender leaves and black-skinned roots.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Chaparral</b></font>

        \nComfrey roots and leaves contain allantoin, a substance that helps new skin cells grow, along with other substances that reduce inflammation and keep skin healthy.
        \n\nComfrey ointments have been used to heal bruises as well as pulled muscles and ligaments, fractures, sprains, strains, and osteoarthritis.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
    \nHistorically, some people have eaten comfrey leaves as a vegetable.
        \n\nTraditional healers have also used oral preparations of comfrey to treat stomach issues, such as ulcers, colitis, and diarrhea.
        \n\nYou can also drink dried comfrey root and leaves as tea.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nComfrey has toxic substances that can cause severe liver damage and even death.
        \n\nYou should never take comfrey by mouth. The toxic substances in comfrey can be absorbed by the skin.
        \n\nEven creams and ointments should be used for only a short time, and only under a doctor\'s supervision.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="ephedra_content"><font size="14"><b>Ephedra (SEphedra equisetina Bge.)</b>
    is a stimulant herb usually from the stem and branches of Ephedra sinica. Most ephedra species contain the chemical ephedrine.

        \n\nThe herb ephedra, also known as ma huang, is a small, twiggy shrub native to Asia, where it has a long history of medicinal use, as documented in ancient medical treatises from India and China.
        \n\nTraditional Chinese and Indian medicine uses the branches of the herb to treat colds and wheezing and as a diuretic.
        \n\nModern European practitioners of herbal medicine use ephedra only to treat symptoms of respiratory diseases (such as bronchial asthma).

        \n\nThe speed-like drug contains the chemical ephedrine, an amphetamine-like compound closely related to adrenaline.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Ephedra</b></font>

        \nEphedra (Ephedra sinica), also called ma huang, is an herb that has been used in Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) for more than 5,000 years, primarily to treat asthma, bronchitis, and hay fever.
        \n\nEphedra is also prescribed for symptoms of cold and flu, including nasal congestion, cough, fever, and chills.

        \n\nIt stimulates the heart, lungs, and nervous system. People use ephedra for weight loss and athletic performance.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThe young stems and branchlets are the parts used for medicinal preparations.
    \n\nEphedra can come in dried or liquid form. It can be taken as a tablet, capsule, or as a tea to drink.

        \n\nEphedra should be used only on a short-term basis because prolonged use may lead to addiction. The amount of time considered safe, however, is not clear.
        \n\nUse of ephedra should take place only under the guidance and supervision of an appropriately-trained specialist.
        \n\nEphedra should be taken between meals, without food.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nEphedra can produce side effects, such as irritability, restlessness, anxiety, insomnia, headaches, nausea, vomiting, and urinary problems.
        \n\nMore serious side effects include high blood pressure, rapid or irregular heartbeat, stroke, seizures, addiction, and even death.
        \n\nTaking ephedra with other stimulants like caffeine increases the risk of severe side effects.
        \n\nDo not take products that contain ephedra or its active ingredients.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="germander_content"><font size="14"><b>Germander (Teucrium)</b>
    is a cosmopolitan genus of flowering plants in the family Lamiaceae, commonly known as germanders.
        \n\nThe parts that grow above the ground are used to make medicine.
        \n\nThis is a large genus of evergreens, from ground covers to shrubs to sub shrubs.

        \n\nThe plant that has been used since ancient times as a folk medicine. It has been used to prepare tea with purported choleretic and antiseptic properties.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Germander</b></font>

        \nThe parts that grow above the ground are used to make medicine.
        \n\nDespite serious safety concerns, people take germander for treating gallbladder conditions, fever, stomachaches, and mild diarrhea; as a digestive aid, germ-killer, and \“rinse for gout;\” and to help with weight loss

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nGermander can be propagated via seed and takes about 30 days to germinate, or you may also use cuttings in the spring and/or divide in the fall.
        \n\nPlants should be spaced 6 inches (15 cm.) apart for a hedge with the addition of some organic matter worked into the soil.

        \n\nCut back the entire germander plant if it\'s overgrown or the stems appear leggy and weak after flowering.
        \n\nRemove up to half the plant\'s height, using sharp hedging shears, and shape the shrub lightly to maintain its dense form.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nThe U.S. still allows germander to be used in small amounts as a flavoring agent in alcoholic beverages.
        \n\nThe safety concern is that germander has caused several cases of liver disease (hepatitis) and death.
        \n\n<b>Germander shouldn\'t be used by anyone.</b>\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="golden_ragwort_content"><font size="14"><b>Golden ragwort (Packera aurea)</b>
    is a perennial flower in the family Asteraceae.

        \n\nGolden Ragwort is a beautiful plant in flower and makes an effective groundcover even in dry shade conditions.
        \n\nIt is found growing in forests, swamps, ravines, or riparian areas in eastern North America to Texas as an herbaceous flowering plant.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Germander</b></font>

        \nDespite serious safety concerns, people take golden ragwort to treat diabetes, high blood pressure, water retention, bleeding, chest congestion, and spasms.
        \n\nWomen use golden ragwort for treating irregular or painful menstrual periods and symptoms of menopause. They also use it to reduce pain and ease childbirth.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nExternally apply in form of ointments and infusions to cure wounds and ulcers
        \n\nUse it as a douche for treating excessive vaginal discharge and leucorrhoea.

    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nGolden ragwort contains eight proven types of pyrrolizidine alkaloids and ten more that have not yet been proven.
        \n\nThese alkaloids cause a condition called pyrrolizidine alkalosis, which can damage the liver permanently and is fatal if enough golden ragwort is consumed.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="pennyroyal_content"><font size="14"><b>Pennyroyal (Mentha pulegium)</b>
    commonly pennyrile, also called mosquito plant and pudding grass, is a species of flowering plant in the mint family, Lamiaceae, native to Europe, North Africa, and the Middle East.
        \n\nCrushed pennyroyal leaves emit a very strong fragrance similar to spearmint.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Germander</b></font>

        \nSome people use it as a stimulant and to counteract weakness.
        \n\nPennyroyal is applied to the skin to kill germs, keep insects away, and treat skin diseases.
        \n\nIt is also used topically for gout, venomous bites, and mouth sores; and as a flea-killing bath.
        \n\nIn foods, pennyroyal is used for flavoring.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nIn manufacturing, pennyroyal oil is used as a dog and cat flea repellent, and as a fragrance for detergents, perfumes, and soaps.

        \n\nPennyroyal oil is not recommended for internal or topical use. There are no clinical studies of pennyroyal herbal tea to provide dosing guidance.

        \n\nSome people use it as a stimulant and to counteract weakness. Pennyroyal is applied to the skin to kill germs, keep insects away, and treat skin diseases.
    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nIt can cause serious liver and kidney damage, as well as nervous system damage.
        \n\nOther side effects include stomach pain, nausea, vomiting, burning of the throat, fever, confusion, restlessness, seizures, dizziness, vision and hearing problems, high blood pressure, lung failure, and death.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="sassafras_content"><font size="14"><b>Sassafras (Sassafras albidum)</b>
    is a genus of three extant and one extinct species of deciduous trees in the family Lauraceae, native to eastern North America and eastern Asia.
        \n\nThe genus is distinguished by its aromatic properties, which have made the tree useful to humans.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Sassafras</b></font>

        \nThe root bark is used to make medicine. Despite serious safety concerns, people use sassafras for many conditions, but there is no good scientific evidence to support these uses.
        \n\nIn beverages and candy, sassafras was used in the past to flavor root beer. It was also used as a tea.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nMedicinally, sassafras has been applied to insect bites and stings to relieve symptoms.
        \n\nThe leaves and pith, when dried and powdered, have been used as a thickener in soups.

        \n\nSome people apply sassafras directly to the skin to treat skin problems, achy joints (rheumatism), swollen eyes, sprains, and insect bites or stings.
        \n\nSassafras oil is also applied to the skin to kill germs and head lice.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nThe safrole in sassafras root bark and oil can cause cancer and liver damage.
        \n\nConsuming just 5 mL of sassafras oil can kill an adult.
        \n\nSassafras can cause sweating and hot flashes. High amounts can cause vomiting, high blood pressure, hallucinations, and other severe side effects.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="sweet_flag_content"><font size="14"><b>Sweet flag (Acorus calamus)</b>
    is a species of flowering plant with psychoactive chemicals. It is a tall wetland monocot of the family Acoraceae, in the genus Acorus.

        \n\nSweet flag is a perennial, rhizomatous, iris-like herb. The erect, sharp-pointed, sword-shaped leaves fan- out from a pinkish base and grow to 5 feet in length.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Sassafras</b></font>

         \nVacha powder can be used on the skin due to its anti-inflammatory property. It inhibits the mediators responsible for causing inflammation and thereby manages inflammation

        \n\n1. Maintains Healthy Stomach
        \n2. Sweet Flag prevents hair lice
        \n3. Sweet Flag good for throat conditions and speech
        \n4. Fights Depression, Epilepsy and Boosting Memory
        \n5. Prevents infection, Inflammation and Pain
        \n6. Sweet Flag Helps In Childbirth

        \n\nSweet flag gives instant relief in stomach problems. It clears a swollen and uncomfortable stomach and also relieves headache related with weak digestion.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nVacha is used to produce a natural binder. This is a good alternative for the artificial ones and can be extracted by burning a piece of vacha churna and then rubbing it on sandalwood stone.
        \n\nIt is safe and good for being applied to children.


    <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
    \nThe most common side effect from calamus is vomiting. Fast heart rate and slowed intestinal movements have also been reported.

        \n\nCalamus is LIKELY UNSAFE when taken by mouth. It can cause kidney damage, shaking, and seizures.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>
</resources>