<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="acapulco_content"><font size="14"><b>Acapulco (Senna alata)</b>
          is an important medicinal tree, as well as an ornamental flowering plant in the subfamily Caesalpinioideae.
        \n\nIt also known as emperor\'s candlesticks, candle bush, candelabra bush, Christmas candles, empress candle plant, ringworm shrub, or candletree.
        \n\nIt is distributed in the tropical and humid regions.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Acapulco</b></font>
        \nThe plant is traditionally used in the treatment of typhoid, diabetes, malaria, asthma, ringworms, tinea infections, scabies, blotch, herpes, and eczema.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \n1. Remove the leaflets from the rachis of a mature leaf.
        \n2. Wash the mature leaflets thoroughly to remove dust, dirt and debris.
        \n3. In the clay, enamel, or stainless steel pot, place one glassful of closely packed chopped leaves (350 ml glass) and add 2 glasses (around 700ml) of clean water . Use the same glass for measuring the leaves and water.
        \n4. Cook the leaves and bring to a rolling boil.
        \n5. When the fluid is reduced to half, remove the decoction from the fire and cool slightly.
        \n6. Strain the mixture using cheesecloth and press the cut leaves in the strainer to make sure to get as much liquid out of them.
        \n7. Place the liquid in a clean container (bottle/jar with cover). Label the container clearly as \"Akapulko\".

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nIt can cause some side effects including stomach discomfort, cramps, and diarrhea.
        \n\nSenna is possibly unsafe when used for longer than 1 week or in doses above 34.4 mg sennosides twice daily.
        \n\nLong-term use can cause the bowels to stop functioning normally and might cause dependence on laxatives.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="bitter_melon_content"><font size="14"><b>Bitter melon (Momordica charantia)</b>
        is a tropical and subtropical vine of the family Cucurbitaceae, widely grown in Asia, Africa, and the Caribbean for its edible fruit.
        \n\nIts many varieties differ substantially in the shape and bitterness of the fruit.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Bitter melon</b></font>
        \n1. Packs Several Important Nutrients
        \n2. Can Help Reduce Blood Sugar
        \n3. May Have Cancer-Fighting Properties
        \n4. Could Decrease Cholesterol Levels
        \n5. May Aid Weight Loss
        \n6. Versatile and Delicious

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nBitter melon can be enjoyed raw or cooked in various recipes.
        \n\nIn fact, it can be pan-fried, steamed, baked, or even hollowed out and stuffed with your choice of fillings.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nConsuming high amounts of bitter melon or taking bitter melon supplements may be associated with several adverse effects.
        \n\nIn particular, bitter melon has been linked to diarrhea, vomiting, and stomach pain
        \n\nIt\’s also not recommended for women who are pregnant, as its long-term effects on health have not been extensively studied.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="chaste_tree_content"><font size="14"><b>Chaste tree (Vitex agnus-castus)</b>
        is a native of the Mediterranean region.
        \n\nIt is one of the few temperate-zone species of Vitex, which is on the whole a genus of tropical and sub-tropical flowering plants.
        \n\nChaste tree is a shrub that bears violet flowers and berries. It\'s also called vitex agnus-castus. The medicinal parts are the dried fruit and leaves.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Chaste tree</b></font>
        \nChaste tree has been used to treat menstrual cycle problems and pain, premenstrual syndrome, and menopause.
        Chaste tree berries may help stimulate progesterone.
        \n\nThis is a female hormone that rises 2 weeks before menstruation. It may help normalize estrogen and progesterone.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nCrude herb extract: Take 20-240mg by mouth per day, divided in 2 to 3 doses.
        \n\nFluid extract: Take up to 40 drops by mouth per day.
        \n\nDried fruit extract: Take 1.6-3ml by mouth up to two times a day.
        \n\nTincture: Take 35-45 drops by mouth up to three times a day.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nChaste tree has no serious side effects.
        \n\nMild side effects can include nausea, stomach issues, diarrhea, and itchy rash.
        \n\nWomen who are pregnant or breastfeeding should not use chaste tree.
        \n\nIt isn\'t known if chaste tree is safe for children.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="fukien_tea_tree_content"><font size="14"><b>Fukien tea tree (Ehretia microphylla)</b>
        also known as the Fukien tea tree or Philippine tea tree, is a species of flowering plant in the borage family, Boraginaceae.
        \n\nalso known as the Fukien tea tree or Philippine tea tree, is a species of flowering plant in the borage family, Boraginaceae.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Fukien tea tree</b></font>
        \nIn the Philippines, the plant is considered as one of the most important medicinal plants.
        \n\nThe leaves are used in the treatment of cough, diarrhoea, colic, and dysentery.
        \n\nThe root is an antidote to plant-based poisoning and is used against haemorrhage and for cleaning the body after giving birth.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nThe leaves are used in the treatment of cough, diarrhoea, colic, and dysentery.
        \n\nThe root is an antidote to plant-based poisoning and is used against haemorrhage and for cleaning the body after giving birth.

        \n\nCan you make tea from a Fukien Tea?

        \n\nFresh, well chopped leaves can be boiled for around 15 minutes, or dried crushed leaves can be prepared in a way as green tea, to make refreshing, caffeine-free drink, delightful both hot and cold.
        \n\nIts tiny stony berry fruits are edible.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nFukien tea tree is not known to be harmful when taken in recommended dosages.
        \nHowever, individuals should always take caution before using for any treatment.
        \n\nAllergies. In rare cases, Fukien tea tree has caused allergic reactions when applied to the skin.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="garlic_content"><font size="14"><b>Garlic (Allium sativum)</b>
        is a species of bulbous flowering plant in the genus Allium.
        Its close relatives include the onion, shallot, leek, chive, Welsh onion and Chinese onion.

        \n\nIt has been used by humans for thousands of years and was used in Ancient Egypt for both culinary purposes and its health and therapeutic benefits.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Garlic</b></font>
        \n1. Garlic contains compounds with potent medicinal properties
        \n2. Garlic is highly nutritious but has very few calories
        \n3. Garlic can help protect against illness, including the common cold
        \n4. The active compounds in garlic can reduce blood pressure
        \n5. Garlic improves cholesterol levels, which may lower the risk of heart disease
        \n6. Garlic contains antioxidants that may help prevent Alzheimer’s disease and dementia
        \n7. Garlic may help you live longer
        \n8. Athletic performance might be improved with garlic supplements
        \n9. Eating garlic may help detoxify heavy metals in the body
        \n10. Garlic may improve bone health
        \n11. Garlic is easy to include in your diet and adds flavor

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nUses: Garlic is most often used as a flavoring agent but can also be eaten as a vegetable.

        \n\nIt is used to flavor many foods, such as salad dressings, vinaigrettes, marinades, sauces, vegetables, meats, soups, and stews.
        \n\nIt is often used to make garlic butter and garlic toast.

        \n\nA common way to use garlic is to press a few cloves of fresh garlic with a garlic press, then mix it with extra virgin olive oil and a bit of salt.\n\n
        This works as a very simple and nutritious salad dressing.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nGarlic has been used safely for up to 7 years.
        It can cause side effects such as bad breath, heartburn, gas, and diarrhea.
        \n\nThese side effects are often worse with raw garlic. Garlic might also increase the risk of bleeding and cause allergic reactions in some people.\n\n

</font>
    </string>

        <string name="guava_content"><font size="14"><b>Guava (Psidium guajava)</b>
            \nis a common tropical fruit cultivated in many tropical and subtropical regions.
            \n\nThe common guava Psidium guajava is a small tree in the myrtle family, native to Mexico, Central America, the Caribbean and northern South America

            \n\nGuava fruits are amazingly rich in antioxidants, vitamin C, potassium, and fiber. This remarkable nutrient content gives them many health benefits.

            <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Guava</b></font>
            \n1. May Help Lower Blood Sugar Levels
            \n2. May Boost Heart Health
            \n3. May Help Relieve Painful Symptoms of Menstruation
            \n4. May Benefit Your Digestive System
            \n5. May Aid Weight Loss
            \n6. May Have an Anticancer Effect
            \n7. May Help Boost Your Immunity
            \n8. Eating Guavas May Be Good for Your Skin

            <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
            \nThe fruit is commonly eaten fresh or made into beverages, jams, and other foods.
            \n\nVarious parts of the plant, including the leaf and the fruit, are used as medicine.
            \n\nPeople use guava leaf for stomach and intestinal conditions, pain, diabetes, and wound healing. The fruit is used for high blood pressure.

            <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
            \nGuava leaf extract might cause temporary nausea or stomach pain in some people.
            \n\nGuava leaf extract is possibly safe when applied to the skin or inside the mouth as a rinse. It might cause skin irritation in some people.\n\n

        </font>
        </string>

    <string name="pepper_elder_content"><font size="14"><b>Guava (Psidium guajava)</b>
        is an annual, shallow-rooted herb, usually growing to a height of about 15 to 45 cm, it is characterized by succulent stems, shiny, heart-shaped, fleshy leaves and tiny, dot-like seeds attached to several fruiting spikes.
        \n\nIt has a mustard-like odor when crushed.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Pepper elder</b></font>
        \nPellucida has been used for treating abdominal pain, abscesses, acne, boils, colic, fatigue, gout, headache, renal disorders, and rheumatic joint pain.
        \n\nIn Bolivia, Alteños Indians use the whole plant to stop hemorrhages.
        \n\nThe roots are used to treat fevers and the aerial parts are used as dressing for wounds.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nMedicinal uses: In South America, Shiny Bush is used medicinally.

        \n\nA solution of the fresh juice of stem and leaves is used against eye inflammation.

        \n\nIt is also been applied against coughing, fever, common cold, headache, sore throat, diarrhea, against kidney - and prostate problems and against high blood pressure.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nThe plant has a strong mustard-like odor and may cause asthma-like symptoms in patients with known hypersensitivity reactions to the plant species.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="rangoon_creeper_content"><font size="14"><b>Rangoon creeper (Combretum indicum)</b>
        , is a vine with red flower clusters which is native to tropical Asia.
        \n\nThe stems have fine yellow hairs with occasional spines forming on the branches.
        \n\nRangoon creeper blooms white at onset and gradually darkens to pink, then finally red as it reaches maturity.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Rangoon creeper</b></font>
        \nApart from a beautiful flower with a wonderful aroma, Madhumalti Plant, or Rangoon Creeper is proven to be beneficial in various medical sectors.
        \n\nThis creeper plant has many medicinal values in it and is used to treat many health problems.
        \n\nIt’s every part serves some therapeutic benefits.


        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \n<b>Treats skin problems</b>: Rangoon Creeper’s leaves are used for skin problems such as boils and ulcers in the form of juice. It works effectively to settle boils and abscesses.

        \n\n<b>Remedy to treat headaches</b>: It is also used for headache and applies on the forehead, which can work efficiently in reducing headaches.

        \n\n<b>Remedy to treat Dysuria or painful urination</b>: You can also make a tea by boiling the leaves which help to get relief from pain while urinating.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nIn large doses they cause hiccups, dizziness, vomiting, and pain in the abdomen, diarrhea and even unconsciousness.
        \n\nAn allergic reaction can cause skin rashes with or without itching, painful swelling of ankles and increase body temperature.
        \n\nAvoid heavy consumption of Rangoon creeper herbs when pregnant and while breast feeding.\n\n
    </font>
    </string>

    <string name="sambong_content"><font size="14"><b>Sambong (Blumea balsamifera)</b>
        is a flowering plant belonging to the genus Blumea of the family Asteraceae. It is also known as Ngai camphor and sambong.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nBenefits of Sambong</b></font>
        \nAs a diuretic, sambong is an herb used to treat urolithiasis (urinary tract or kidney stones) and urinary tract infections, and thus reduces high blood pressure.
        \n\nSambong works as an expectorant, an anti-diarrheal and an anti-spasmotic, all of which treat some symptoms of the common cold.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nHow to use</b></font>
        \nPreparation and Use: A decoction (boil in water) of Sambong leaves as like tea and drink a glass 3 or 4 times a day.
        \n\nThe leaves can also be crushed or pounded and mixed with coconut oil.
        \n\nFor headaches, apply crushed and pounded leaves on forehead and temples.

        <font size ="18"><b>\n\nPotential side effects</b></font>
        \nSambong can cause allergic reaction for people sensitive to ragweed plants and its relatives.
        \n\nSide effect may include itching and skin irritation.
        \n\nStore at temperatures not exceeding 30°C.\n\n

    </font>
    </string>


</resources>